## Minh Nguyen



nguyendm77@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/minhd-nguyen



4259519318



https://www.minhdnguyen.com

#### Summary

Software developer providing influent experiences with the latest front-end and back-end programming languages, tools, and methodologies including Javascript, Python, Java, HTML, CSS, SASS, ¡Query, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQL, AngularJS, NodeJS, ReactJS, TypeScript, WordPress, Git, Github, and Agile/Scrum.

5+ years of experience in manufacture, lab, reliability test, familiar with Lab-view. Experienced hardware computer with strong skills in developing and implementing commercial networking environments.

Testing, troubleshooting, debugging with 12+ years of experience in the computing sectors, aerospace, and medical device.

Here is my recent accomplishment:

1. I built the GA Motivate app with the team in the GA hackathon which using NodeJS for the backend, ReactJS for the frontend.

https://ga-motivate.herokuapp.com/login

2. I built Terra app using NextJs.

https://terra-ten.vercel.app/

3. I built Covid-19 tracking using React Js, D3 library.

https://covid-tracker-iota-nine.vercel.app/

4. I built Stay Inside app using NodeJs for the backend, ReactJs for the frontend.

https://stay-inside-meet-up.netlify.app/login

5. I built myMelody app using Spotify API with ReactJs.

https://mindmelody.herokuapp.com/

#### **Experience**



### Software Engineer

**General Assembly** 

May 2020 - Present (9 months +)

Software development experiences with 500 hours training full-time and full-stack program conducted in a remote setting, providing experience with the latest front and back-end programming languages, tools, and methodologies including Javascript, Python, Java, HTML, CSS, SASS, jQuery, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQL, AngularJS, NodeJS, ReactJS, TypeScript, WordPress, Git, Github, and Agile/Scrum.

#### XR Lab/Test Engineer

Microsoft

Oct 2018 - Apr 2020 (1 year 7 months)

Worked in Reliability Lab of Surface Hub team which are including managing the lab; developing, excusing, and reporting test case; recording and analyzing failure:

- Verifying and performing predefined protocols, CAD drawings, electronic schematics, electrical diagrams, work instructions, or other specifications in accordance with established lab procedures.
- Set up, operate, and/or maintain test equipment and tools such as vibration, shock, drop, TH/TC chamber, thermocouples, acceleration, color measurement, digital imaging measurement, rotation, life test, tapping, compute/non compute functional.
- Testing material: PCB, hardware, touchscreen, accessories such as cable, stylus pen, bezel, mask, steel frame.
- Document and record test data in compliance with quality requirements and compare results against predetermined limits.
- Reporting analyzing failure, communicating problems/issues, and test non-conformance findings with Reliability Engineer, DEV Team.
- Managing test schedules to meet test completion delivery dates.
- Adhere to environmental and safety procedures associated with lab processes and procedures: managing work request, raw data (test report, test case status), inventory DUT (device under test), 5S, Safety lab.

#### REPAIR STATION MANAGER

AIRCRAFT CABIN SYSTEMS, LLC

Jan 2018 - Oct 2018 (10 months)

Repair Station Manager / FAA Accountable Manager role:

- Management: Administered profit and loss, analyzed, forecasting & managing the budget. Repair and Production quality standards and correct execution of daily operations by using ERP systems for processing and Quality streamline efficiency.
- Supervisor responsibility and tech doing work on repair unit, oversee the actual repair, verify and revise response by ATP (Acceptance Test Procedure), CMM (Circuit Manual Manufacture).
- Operating Repair Station by being overall responsible for build schedule/repairs of customer inflight entertainment custom LCD monitors for over 100 different customers and 35 different aircraft types which are including Gulfstream, Rockwell Collins, Air Nippon Airline, Japan Airline, China Airline Services, etc.
- Qualification, Accountable of FAA /EASA certify release certificate which is including COC (Certificate of Conformance), ARC (Authorize Release Certificate) according FAA part 145, 8130-3.



#### Test Leader

Qualitel Corp.

Sep 2015 - Dec 2017 (2 years 4 months)

- Manage testing and troubleshooting for Innovative, Gogo, Astronic, Technofan, Korry, and Lucent (medical device): setup test station, debug, programming, ATP test (Specialized functional testing), Halt/Hass test (changing temperature, vibration, shock test), Hi-Pot test (High-voltage), ICT test(incircuit test).
- Operating test case with DMM, hand tool, microscope, oscilloscope, solder, debug error by software, X-ray with CT (computer tomography).



#### **Engineering Test Technician**

Various Companies

Sep 2014 - Aug 2015 (1 year)

Aerospace: assembly, testing and troubleshooting device including CSNM, Light control, Wireless Access point, Sound system, Touchscreen, Bluetooth Sky Fair, Switch Panel.

Medical device: assembly, testing and troubleshooting device including Anesthesia systems, Blease700 Series, Blease900 Series.



#### Senior IT & Systems Engineer

MK Tech

Mar 2001 - Aug 2014 (13 years 6 months)

- Conduct research, designing and developing, testing and supervising the installation of computer hardware. Assigned personnel to projects and determined their management duties and responsibilities.
- Facilitate the communications link between organization and customers. Supervised the management of hardware inventory purchase and sales.
- Design a variety of computer programs for use in security, telecommunication and other low voltage systems such as audio/video and lighting. Setup network with TCP/IP, DHCP, VPN, LAN, WAN.
- Maintain a standard configuration of all equipment. Responsible for quality control as it relates to equipment inventory and skilled personnel, including technical support.
- Performed system administration including database recovery for customer accounts.

#### **Education**



#### Bellevue College

Associate of Arts and Sciences - AAS, Computer Science

2017 - 2019

Fundamental of computer science: algorithm, statistics, analysis, Java programming language.



#### Ho Chi Minh University of Technology

Bachelor's degree, Information Technology

1995 - 2000

Fundamental of computer engineer: computer hardware, computer structure, database, data structure, basic of programming language C, C#.

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



IPC-A-610 - Association Connecting Electronics Industries

Issued Mar 2017 - Expires Mar 2019 610MS 3857146334



Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt - Everett Community College



Professional Advanced Management Program - EDS Business Solutions GmbH

- Software Engineer Immersive Remote General Assembly
- Learn SQL Course Codecademy
- JavaScript Essentials Udemy
- HTM5 Programming Udemy
- Learning SQL Programming LinkedIn AX4LT1Y8dD\_VnP9q-Jh6Mr6GXa0m
- NASBA SQL Programming LinkedIn
  ARWYUrl2ao0BEj6SVr3kzSVwEWfP
- Succeeding in Web Development: Full Stack and Front End LinkedIn AaD5odCYV9xmWmtU9HR1zt52nlca
- Programming Foundations: Fundamentals LinkedIn Ac3qO6YDBRtc9kj8pEfZZKSUObSs
- CSS Essential Training LinkedIn
  ATwN9WYYZDbCi2-qsLAFJXNI0mSt
- HTML Essential Training LinkedIn
  AbkdQcVET8UszHOT7\_J8xl3DlTwr
- JavaScript Essential Training LinkedIn
  AaDoTsw-XkmH1wcB5Ulous0mvojN
- SQL: Data Reporting and Analysis LinkedIn AZQ\_vGxHlew8bK79clkbYeH8EYcU
- Learning Python LinkedIn
  AelNEuTkzsl4YsZVTQGNONh7pwVO
- Learning Java LinkedIn
  AXa6n9OMvsi4QitkMs7Es92yaonn
- Programming Foundations: Web Security LinkedIn

# Programming Foundations: Databases - LinkedIn AfeZhV7nv9adJkPmJlU6AbYqKyLi

#### **Skills**

Software Development • Computer Science • Computer Engineering • Project Management • Lean Manufacturing • Agile Methodologies • Web Development • Front-end Development • Analytical Skills • Algorithms